Sreenadh Madappura

Java Full Stack Developer

Evere, Brussels, Belgium • +32-465271150 • sreenadhm01@gmail.com





m sreenadh-m



sreenadh.dev



sr33nadhm

Fullstack developer with more than 3 years of experience implementing both frontend and backend systems in Java, JavaScript and Typescript; led re-architecture of current platform that plays a critical role in the organization and caters to 100000+ users, increasing efficiency by 20 percent.

SKILLS

Programming Languages - Java, JavaScript

User Interface Development - Angular, React.is, MobX, Material UI, HTML, CSS, iQuery

Backend Development – Java Spring Boot, Node.js, Express.js

Database Management - MySQL, DB2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

DB middleware – Hibernate, JPA, Knex.js, Objection.js

Test frameworks - jest, junit

Message Queues - RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka

Amazon Web Services - DynamoDB, S3, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, CloudFront

Google Cloud Platform - Compute Engine, Cloud Storage, BigQuery

Project Management - GIT, JIRA, Bit Bucket, Confluence

DevOps – Docker, Kubernetes, Concourse, Jenkins

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

May 2021 - Present

IBM India Private Limited, Bangalore, India

Handling IBM internal application UI development in Ext. is and backend development in Java Spring Boot, Hibernate and DB2.

Built and deployed 5+ new features which handle core facilities of the organization subdomain.

- Launched the application changes for organization restructure of the company, by deploying key features which helped to manage 25000+ employees...
- Led the migration and **re-architecture** of the application to **IBM Cloud** by modernizing and containerizing the application using **Docker**, **Kubernetes** and **Open Liberty**, increasing the deployment rates to 300%.
- Leading the modernization of the application to Java Spring Boot, reducing the CVE exposure of the application to 0.
- Administering design and code reviews for 3 teams handling 5 projects under the same leadership.

Systems Engineer

August 2019 - May 2021

Infosys Limited, Trivandrum, India

Steered 3 client projects and 1 internal project that cater to 100000+ users, as a full stack web developer. Designed and engineered 10+ applications, programmed scripts in languages like JavaScript and Python.

Client projects include:

Online video platform migration - Brightcove Inc

Handled the position of Full Stack Developer for designing and developing new features and plugins along with a team of 250 members which helped them migrate their content and user information to the target platform.

- Implemented backend applications and more than 22 APIs in Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.
- Programmed 5+ scripts to assist the migration and data validation of 100000+ records.
- Delivered 25+ UI components using React, and integrated with backend, using REST Api.

Infosys Internal OTT based project - Infosys Ltd

Commanded the position of Full Stack Developer for Infosys internal project on OTT technology. Designed, developed and deployed 25+ frontend and backend components.

- Engineered backend services with Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA and MongoDB.
- Written and maintained 50+ automated test cases in **jUnit**.
- Collaborated with the UI design team and generated 15+ UI components in **Angular**.
- Successfully integrated the User Interface with backend services using **REST Api**.
- Actively participated in 100+ code reviews, monitored and ensured coding practices are being followed.

Internet Measurement Platform - Comcast Corporation

Handled the position of Backend Developer for Internet Measurement Platform for this overseas client. Shipped and monitored 10+ new features and scripts.

- Built and screened Node.js applications for monitoring internet speeds, using speedtest SDK.
- Developed and maintained a data pipeline using Scala and Kafka.
- Performed data analytics and report generation using **Elasticsearch** and **Kibana**.
- Generated scripts in **Python** to process 100000+ **JSON** feeds from **Elasticsearch**

Online video platform - Vuclip

Commanded the position of Full Stack Developer for this Singapore based Video platform. streamlined and regulated 25+ features for their backend services.

- Delivered and remodeled more than 15 **Java Spring Boot, Hibernate** and **MySQL** based microservice backend applications.
- Migrated monolithic billing platform services to microservice architecture
- Onboarded more than 4 payment gateway services to the new billing platform.

EDUCATION

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Mysore, India

Master of Computer Applications — Computer Science

August 2017 - May 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Winter Internship - Infosys Ltd

January 2019 - May 2019

Completed the internship with Infosys in their Global Education Center, Mysore which included training in Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Angular. A Capstone project was implemented and submitted as part of the internship.

Microservices with Java, Spring, Docker, Kubernetes - Udemy

Completed certification course from Udemy for Spring Boot Microservices and their containerization using Docker and Kubernetes.

URL: https://ude.mv/UC-95990a70-6e31-44fb-bf87-2852161f0d8f/